THE KODU GAME LAB COMMUNITY CODE OF CONDUCT ("Code of Conduct")
The Code of Conduct outlines the rules that you must follow to help ensure that the Service is fun for everyone. 
A. You will do the following:
•	Be polite and treat others with respect. 
•	Let us know if you encounter content that is offensive - especially if the content is violating the Code of Conduct. 
•	Have fun!
B. You will not do the following:
•	Don't use the Service to do anything illegal. Microsoft is not responsible for your actions and the consequences of your actions while using the Service. 
•	Don't harass, abuse, insult or spam other users, or encourage other users to do so.  Don’t provide any advertising or free offer content that violates any of the other categories outlined here.
•	Don't create a creator name or game content that other users may be offended by. This includes, without limitation, anything related to or suggestive of: hate speech or discriminatory content based on considerations of race, national origin, gender, age, disability, religion, ethnic group, sexual orientation or expression, illegal drugs/controlled substances, or illegal activities. 
•	Don't create a creator name or game content that references controversial religious topics, notorious people, organizations, or sensitive current or historical events that may be considered inappropriate. 
•	Don't distribute, post, publish, upload, disseminate or discuss defamatory, infringing, obscene, sexual or unlawful materials in any format (images, audio, video, text, etc.). Prohibited materials include, without limitation, child sexual abuse content, child pornography, child exploitation, child abuse, child molestation, bestiality, violent and/or gory sexual acts. “Sound alike” words, phrases, or puns that reference these topics are also prohibited.
•	Don’t distribute, post, publish, upload, disseminate or discuss defamatory content (defamation, impersonation, non-consensual pornography, or fraudulent solicitation of money or services).
•	Don’t distribute, post, publish, upload, disseminate or discuss illegal substances, goods and services, such as any content depicting the use of illegal drugs, or sale or goods and/or services related to illegal drugs, including consumption by or sale to minors.
•	Don’t distribute, post, publish, upload, disseminate or discuss threats of violence, terrorism, bullying and/or harassment.
•	Don’t distribute, post, publish, upload, disseminate or discuss terrorist content, such as content posted by a United Nations Security Council Sanctions’ List – recognized terrorist organization or in favor of such a group, and where the content encourages violent action, endorses a terrorist organization or its acts, or encourages people to join a terrorist organization.
•	Don’t distribute, post, publish, upload, disseminate or discuss illegal gambling and gaming.  For clarity, this includes any content promoting or permitting illegal online gambling or gaming to or by minors, or in geographies and in markets where such activities are prohibited by law.
•	Don't post references to websites that violate the Code of Conduct. 
•	Don't give out personal information of other players (such as their real name, address, phone number, credit card number, etc.) in any way (including, without limitation, through the names you create for your creator name or in-game content). This information could be used by other players for illegal or harmful purposes. You should also avoid giving out your own personal information.  Unauthorized solicitation or posting of Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”) is not allowed.
•	Don't post references to materials that could harm other users' computers or would allow others to inappropriately access software or Web sites, including malware (for example, viruses, Trojan horses, worms, time bombs, cancel bots) or any other malicious software programs, degradation or denial of service attacks against Microsoft or users, hacking, identity theft, spam, or enabling the evasion or bypassing of security systems or otherwise tampering with software, servers or websites 
•	Don’t use your account for commercial purposes (including, without limitation, trading services or in-game content for currency or Microsoft Points).
•	Don’t attempt to impose additional terms of use or service that violate, limit, or diminish Microsoft terms of use.
•	Don't impersonate, harass, or defame Microsoft employees, moderators, or staff members. 
C. Consequences of Violations. 
If you violate the Code of Conduct or the Kodu Game Lab Service Agreement, action may be taken against your account, including without limitation the following:
•	Some offenses warrant an immediate permanent suspension, including without limitation: hacking, fraud, severe racial remarks, depictions of nudity, repeated creation of inappropriate creator names or game content, or posting viruses or URLs to viruses.
•	Repeated violations of the Code of Conduct can result in a permanent suspension of your account, or a permanent suspension of any device you are using to connect to the Service.
•	If you create a creator name that has been determined to violate the Kodu Game Lab Service Agreement or Code of Conduct, you will be required to change it.
Microsoft is not obligated to send you a warning before these actions occur. If your account is suspended while participating in a tournament or competition Microsoft assumes no liability in the loss of any potential prizes or recognition related to the tournament or competition. Microsoft is not obligated to monitor every post, but we have the right to remove any post or take action against any user. Microsoft reserves the right to remove at any time, without notice, any user-created content from the Service. Microsoft reserves the right to immediately terminate or suspend a user for violations. Microsoft can contact any Internet Service Provider and provide the ISP with information on illegal activities.
